[Music]
Welcome to busy central launch event
2025 release wave 1. In this session we
will show you one uh on the first side
small improvement in electronic
documents but this is really important
one. So let's start uh with electronic
uh documents in account payable process
in general. Why do we work with account
payable in electronic documents? First,
this is something what is required if
you want to be compliant in many
countries. In many countries, this is
first introduced uh that you must
receive electron documents. So, we
wanted second thing to automate it. So,
you're compliant and you can make
additional
automation and then we made some uh
improvements here. Uh earlier you could
proceed only automatically. So you will
import system will automatically create
your electronic uh purchase electronic
invoice if no errors. So if you already
had item references on GL mapping
everything will be done automatically.
Um what was a small issue here we
couldn't review incoming document before
processing. Even if you could go back
you couldn't see details. Only what you
could do was to download XML and XML is
machine readable format. This is not
human readable format. So now what we
did first we enabled both one step and
two step processing. What does it mean?
You can still continue by default you
will continue the same way will
automatically create if everything exist
but you can turn off it. So system will
work in two steps. So you will just
create a training document and then you
can decide to process and to create
purchase uh purchase invoice in the
business central. So this is important.
So you can do uh on the both of way. But
one more important thing much more
important again now you can review this
document before processing or after
processing never mind you can see
original document. What does it mean?
You have XML but now in a electronic
documents we have actually reading this
XML. So you will have extracted
information from your vendor document um
in the header the most important fields
in the header and you will have
extracted document lines. So you can
even check your lines if this document
is something what you expect from your
vendor if uh price is good if everything
is okay as you agreed and after that you
can continue to proceed and posting
documents. So this is what we want to
show you right now. As I said, small
feature but extremely important because
now you can preview before processing
and posting in a business central uh
upcoming uh documents. So now we'll give
a word my colleague Magnus and he will
show you how it work in a practice.
Thank you Alexander. So uh let's take a
look how that is in the product. With me
today I have a demo tenant with a demo
company demo receive and I will uh
navigate to e documents.
All right. So, here I have a set of uh
inbound e documents that we have
received in our company. And I will just
open up uh one of them number 31
here. And as you can see on the e
documents cards page, we have added uh
this sub form lines that now allows you
to see uh the the lines that were
received in the XML that uh was sent to
you. This works of course for both
processed and unprocessed documents as
Alexander said. In this case, we've
already created the purchase invoice. So
I can open that up and we can see that
it also contains the lines with the the
GL account set. If you want to inspect
further, you can also now go under
related and open up view extracted data.
And from here you will have a mix of
both header information and the line
information for you to go look at before
you decide on whether you want to
process this e document into a purchase
document. As an an additional thing I
just want to quickly mention is that we
have the new and improved fact box for
for the e document card page where you
can now see the service and the locks
are moved to here for you to to view.
But we also have the attachments uh fact
box where you can see that on this e
document we created two PDF attachments
that was embedded in the XML and stored
them so you can open them up and see.
And this one is from Perro that that I
received and you can then inspect uh
that as well. And that is essentially
everything. Alexander back to you. Thank
you Magnus. Yeah, as I said this is on a
first size small improvements but I
think this is XML big because first you
can transfer XML to readable to human
readable uh information and plus we have
this embedded PDF uh inside. So now when
you get the electronic voice if this is
XML PEL with embedded uh PDF system will
extract this PDF and then you can easily
click on this PDF from e documents and
show even original documents there. So
this is again as I said a really
important feature. So uh before I say
thank you, I would like to invite you to
watch another uh sessions related to e
documents because we have so many new uh
features related to electronic documents
in this release. If and if I'm not
wrong, we have six different sessions
related to e documents. So please watch
another session to understand what is
improved in this area. And now thank you
for watching us.